A text file refers to a file that uses
文本文件指使用特定字符集的一种文件
a specific character set and contains no formatting,
不含有任何格式
like italics or bolding.
比如斜体或加粗样式
It also, has no media,
文本文件也没有媒体功能
like images or video.
比如图像或视频
Lines of text are separated by newline characters or backslash end in Python.
在 Python 中 文本行尾采用换行符或反斜线分隔
These characters are invisible in most software applications, like this text editor.
这些字符在大部分软件中都是不可见的 比如 这个文本编辑器
And speaking of text editors,
说到文本编辑器
text files can be viewed and edited in simple text editors, which makes sense.
它可以查看和编辑文本文件 这毫无疑问
Flat files, like our TSB file pictured here,
平面文件 比如此图显示的 TSB 文件
are technically text files,
从技术上讲平面文件也是文本文件的一种
but they have a specific structure.
但是 它们有特定的结构
These Roger Ebert review text files though are just blobs of text,
这些 Roger Ebert 影评文本文件只是一些大对象数据类型文本
no defined structure like the tabular structure in the TSB format.
无定义的结构 比如 TSB 格式的表格结构
Right now, you're going to focus on this no structure,
现在你要关注这个没有结构的文本文件
just a blob of text kind of text file.
它只是一份大对象数据类型文本 是文本文件的一种
But know that all of the techniques you apply here
无论文本是什么结构
can be done with any text file regardless of structure.
此处应用的所有方法对任何文本文件都适用
Regarding the specific character set,
对于特定的字符集
have you ever opened a document and its characters are all garbled like this?
你是否曾经打开某个文件后发现字符都这样混乱？
Like just a bunch of question marks in a row.
就像一串成列的问号“？”
Or a bunch of weird characters like these here.
或是一串奇怪的字符 比如这些
That's because your text editor, browser,
那是因为正在努力读取文档的文本编辑器、浏览器、文字处理器或其它软件
or word processor or whatever else that's trying to read the document is assuming
将字符集位数转换成字母和数字时
the wrong encoding or the wrong scheme for
采用了错误编码方式或
converting the character sets bits to letters and numbers.
采用的方法错误
You simply need to select the right encoding to display the document properly.
你只需选择正确的编码来显示文档即可
Character sets and encodings are two things that
处理文本数据时
every programmer needs to be aware of when working with any text data,
字符集和编码是每位程序员须谨记的事
including flat files like CSV files and also HTML and Json,
包括 CSV、HTML 和 Json 格式的平面文件
the latter most of which we haven't covered yet, but we will soon.
后两者格式尚未提到 不过我们很快就会讲到
I've provided links to two popular articles.
我提供了两篇相关热门文章的链接
This one. And this one.
这篇 还有这篇
These articles make the point loud and clear.
这些文章将论点证明得一清二楚
Take a second to read this.
花上一点时间 阅读这篇文章
This article here by Joel Spolsky is entertaining and lighter on the technical details,
这篇文章由 Joel Spolsky 所写 很有趣
all of which you don't necessarily need to know.
对无关紧要的技术细节轻描淡写
And this second one, which was actually built in response to the first one,
第二篇文章是第一篇文章的回答
fills in the technical gaps.
填补了技术上的空白
Check them both out if you're not familiar with these topics.
如果你对这些话题不熟悉 可以把两篇文章都读读